## DAVID BILSON

WEB DEVELOPER

**\** +2349070678576

https://github.com/davidBilson

davidbilson99@gmail.com

davidbilson.vercel.app

# PROFILE OVERVIEW

As an experienced web developer and technical writer, I have a proven track record of delivering user-friendly and engaging websites. With a keen eye for detail and a passion for creative problem-solving, I work collaboratively to ensure that projects are executed to the highest standard

## **EXPERIENCE**

## Web Administrator (Shopify, SEO) Fyre Skin Brand April 2023 - Present

- As a web administrator, I optimized the Shopify store and associated apps, resulting in an increase in sales. I also optimized the visibility of the Shopify store using SEO best practices, Google keyword planner, and Google Business.
- I designed and implemented a custom booking system, reducing booking errors.
- I managed ongoing website maintenance, troubleshooting issues, and collaborating closely with cross-functional teams. My excellent communication skills ensured alignment on project goals and priorities.

#### Contract Web Developer

#### WorkxieBillionaire 3 months

- Developed website prototype for Workxiebillionaire (using HTML, CSS, JS, React)
- Contributed to the design and layout of the website, including the landing page. I also optimized the responsiveness of the website
- Designed and wrote the white paper for the Genesis AP of the WXB NFT project

#### Web Developer & SEO Strategist

#### EasyDrumming 5 months

- Developed website prototype for Workxiebillionaire (using HTML, CSS, JS, React)
- Contributed to the design and layout of the website, including the landing page. I also optimized the responsiveness of the website
- Designed and wrote the white paper for the Genesis AP of the WXB NFT project

#### Web Development Coach

#### Contract 2021 - Present

- Conducted one-on-one coaching sessions to teach web development skills, including HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.
- Created customized learning plans based on individual student goals and learning styles, and provided feedback on coding projects.

## SKILLS

**JavaScript** 

React

**HTML** 

**CSS** 

Tailwind CSS

SASS

**FireBase** 

**Google Analytics** 

Github

**Technical Writing** 

**SEO** 

**Graphics Design** 

## **EDUCATION**

University of Ilorin

B.Sc. Microbiology

2018 - 2022

## **CERTIFICATION**

Responsive Web Design FreeCodeCamp 2022

Internet / Cyber Security Crash Course AptLearn 2022

Technical Writing Certification Course AptLearn 2022